<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>

<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd" [
        <!ENTITY rfc2119 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2119.xml">
        <!ENTITY rfc2223 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2223.xml">
        <!ENTITY rfc2578 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2578.xml">
        <!ENTITY rfc2579 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2579.xml">
        <!ENTITY rfc2580 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2580.xml">
        <!ENTITY rfc2629 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2629.xml">
        <!ENTITY rfc3410 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.3410.xml">
        <!ENTITY rfc4181 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.4181.xml">
        ]>
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc compact="yes"?>
<?rfc subcompact="no"?>
<?rfc strict="no"?>
<?rfc rfcedstyle="yes"?>
<?rfc comments="yes"?>
<?rfc inline="yes"?>

<!-- Document  section

Specify the category attribute per RFC2026
options are info, std, bcp, or exp.

docname is the name of the output document. This is optional;
the default is to use the base portion of the XML filename.

For Internet-drafts, indicate which intellectual property notice
to use per the rules of RFC3978. The value (as of this template) can be:
    trust200902 -
    noModificationTrust200902 -
    noDerivativesTrust200902 -
    pre5378Trust200902 -

 The Intellectual Property section will be generated automatically by
  XML2RFC, based on the ipr attribute in the rfc element.

If this document obsoletes an RFC, specify the RFC in the "obsoletes" attribute
If this document updates an RFC, specify the RFC in the "updates" attribute
-->
<rfc category="historic" docName="RFC - My Teams" ipr="noModificationTrust200902">
    <front>
        <!--
    Enter the full document title and an abbreviated version
      to use in the page header.
    -->

        <title abbrev="My Teams">My Teams</title>

        <!-- copy the author block as many times as needed, one for each author.-->

        <!-- If the author is acting as editor, use the <role=editor> attribute-->

        <!-- see RFC2223 for guidelines regarding author names -->

        <author fullname="Bourgeois Benjamin" initials="BB" role="editor"
                surname="Bourgeois Benjamin">
            <organization>Epitech</organization>

            <address>

                <email>benjamin.bourgeois@epitech.eu</email>
            </address>
        </author>

        <author fullname="Ettel Jamil" initials="EJ" role="editor"
                surname="Ettel Jamil">
            <organization>Epitech</organization>

            <address>

                <email>jamil.ettel@epitech.eu</email>
            </address>
        </author>

        <author fullname="Lecomte Amaury" initials="LA" role="editor"
                surname="Lecomte Amaury">
            <organization>Epitech</organization>

            <address>

                <email>amaury.lecomte@epitech.eu</email>
            </address>
        </author>

        <!-- month and day will be generated automatically by XML2RFC;
    be sure the year is current.-->

        <date  year="2020" />

        <!--WG name at the upperleft corner of the doc,
    IETF is fine for non-WG IETF submissions -->

        <workgroup>Internet Engineering Task Force</workgroup>

        <keyword>Network Management</keyword>

        <keyword>Management Information Base</keyword>

    </front>

    <middle>
        <section title="Introduction">
            <!--You can echo the abstract in the Introduction, providing citations here,
      but you should provide more than just the abstract. -->

            <t>This memo defines a portion of the Management Information Base (MIB)
                for use with network management protocols. In particular it defines
                objects for managing the [TEMPLATE TODO].</t>

            <t><cref>[TEMPLATE TODO]: describe what functionality will be managed using this MIB
                module. Include citations for protocol specifications, architectures, related MIB modules, and protocol-specific
                management requirements. Provide an overview of why a MIB module is appropriate for this protocol,  whether there is a
                particular aspect of the protocol to be managed, and how the module is expected to be used to
                achieve particular goals. Highlight anything 'different' about the module. For example,
                a read-only MIB module.</cref></t>

        </section>

        <section title="Conventions">
            <t><cref>[TEMPLATE TODO] This boilerplate should be used if the RFC2119 key words
                are used in the internet draft. The text in this section has been
                copied from the official boilerplate, and should not be modified. </cref></t>

            <t>The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT",
                "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and "OPTIONAL" in this
                document are to be interpreted as described in BCP 14, RFC 2119 <xref
                        target="RFC2119"></xref>.</t>

        </section>

        <!-- ********************************************* -->

        <section title="Overview">

            <t></t>

        </section>


        <section title="Client">

            <section title="Overview">

                <t>
                    The client must be able to connect to one server, to send
                    multiple command to the server, and to receive reply
                    from server and display this information.
                </t>
                <t>
                    The client must send command in a specific format describe
                    later and decode response in a human read format.
                </t>
                <t>
                    You can find commands and reply-codes in Commands
                    Section(6) and Reply-Codes Section(7)
                </t>
                <t></t>

            </section>

            <section title="Send">

                <t>
                    The client must send command to server in a particular
                    format. Each command must be send with a specific header
                    like follow :
                </t>

                <figure>
                    <artwork>
<![CDATA[
    typedef struct __attribute__((packed))
    {
        unsigned char command;
        int message_size;
    } client_request_t;
]]>
                    </artwork>
                </figure>

                <t>
                    command : An unsigned char among this list corresponding to
                    the command associate with the request. Commands allowed
                    are :
                </t>

                <figure>
                    <artwork>
                        <![CDATA[
    enum command_code_e {
        UNKNOWN,
        HELP,
        LOGIN,
        LOGOUT,
        USERS,
        USER,
        SEND,
        MESSAGES,
        SUBSCRIBE,
        SUBSCRIBED,
        UNSUBSCRIBE,
        USE,
        CREATE,
        LIST,
        INFO
    };
]]>
                    </artwork>
                </figure>

                <t>
                    message size : The total size in bytes of all arguments
                    of the associated command after the header.
                </t>

                <t>
                    <list style="symbols">
                        <t>
                            The client can send information in one time or in
                            multiple time.
                        </t>
                        <t>
                            The client should verify the correct number and
                            type of each argument of the associated command.
                            There is another verification server side.
                        </t>
                    </list>
                </t>

            </section>

            <section title="Receive">

                <t></t>

            </section>

        </section>

        <section title="Server">

            <t><cref>[TEMPLATE TODO]: The narrative part should include a section that specifies the
                relationship (if any) of the MIB modules contained in this internet drafts to
                other standards, particularly to standards containing other MIB
                modules. If the MIB modules defined by the specification import
                definitions from other MIB modules or are always implemented in
                conjunction with other MIB modules, then those facts should be noted in
                the narrataive section, as should any special interpretations of objects
                in other MIB modules. Note that citations may NOT be put into the MIB
                module portions of the internet draft, but documents used for Imported items
                are Normative references, so the citations should exist in the narrative
                section of the internet draft. The preferred
                way to fill in a REFERENCE clause in a MIB module is of the form: "Guidelines
                for Writing an IANA Considerations Section in RFCs", RFC2434, section 2.3.</cref></t>

            <section title="Overview">

                <t><cref>Example: The Interface MIB [RFC2863] requires that any
                    MIB module which is an adjunct of the Interface MIB clarify specific
                    areas within the Interface MIB. These areas were intentionally left
                    vague in the Interface MIB to avoid over-constraining the MIB, thereby
                    precluding management of certain media-types. Section 4 of [RFC2863] enumerates several
                    areas which a media-specific MIB must clarify. The implementor is
                    referred to [RFC2863] in order to understand the
                    general intent of these areas.</cref></t>

            </section>

            <section title="Send">

                <t><cref>[TEMPLATE TODO]: Citations are not permitted within a MIB module, but any
                    module mentioned in an IMPORTS clause or document mentioned in a
                    REFERENCE clause is a Normative reference, and must be cited someplace
                    within the narrative sections. If there are imported items in the MIB
                    module, such as Textual Conventions, that are not already cited, they
                    can be cited in text here. Since relationships to other MIB modules
                    should be described in the narrative text, this section is typically
                    used to cite modules from which Textual Conventions are imported. Example: "The following MIB module IMPORTS objects from SNMPv2-SMI [RFC2578],
                    SNMPv2-TC [RFC2579],
                    SNMPv2-CONF [RFC2580], and IF-MIB [RFC2863]."</cref></t>

            </section>

            <section title="Receive">

                <t><cref>[TEMPLATE TODO]: Citations are not permitted within a MIB module, but any
                    module mentioned in an IMPORTS clause or document mentioned in a
                    REFERENCE clause is a Normative reference, and must be cited someplace
                    within the narrative sections. If there are imported items in the MIB
                    module, such as Textual Conventions, that are not already cited, they
                    can be cited in text here. Since relationships to other MIB modules
                    should be described in the narrative text, this section is typically
                    used to cite modules from which Textual Conventions are imported. Example: "The following MIB module IMPORTS objects from SNMPv2-SMI [RFC2578],
                    SNMPv2-TC [RFC2579],
                    SNMPv2-CONF [RFC2580], and IF-MIB [RFC2863]."</cref></t>

            </section>
        </section>

        <section title="Commands">
            <t><cref>This section contains the actual MIB module(s).
                These MIB modules MUST be written in SMIv2 [RFC2578] [RFC2579]
                [RFC2580]. See Section 4 of RFC 4181 for guidelines on SMIv2 usage.
                See Appendix C of RFC 4181 for suggested naming conventions.</cref></t>

            <figure>
                <artwork><![CDATA[
[TEMPLATE TODO]: put your valid MIB module here.
A list of tools that can help automate the process of
checking MIB definitions can be found at the OPS
Area web site.]]></artwork>
            </figure>
        </section>

        <section title="Reply Codes">

            <figure>
                <preamble></preamble>

                <artwork><![CDATA[
                 The MIB module in this document uses the following IANA-assigned
                 OBJECT IDENTIFIER values recorded in the SMI Numbers registry:

                 Descriptor        OBJECT IDENTIFIER value
                 ----------        -----------------------
                 sampleMIB         { mib-2 XXX }
                    ]]></artwork>

                            <postamble></postamble>
            </figure>

            <t><cref>[TEMPLATE TODO] Each internet draft that defines one or more MIB modules MUST
                contain a section that discusses security considerations relevant to
                those modules. This section MUST be patterned after the latest approved
                template (available at the OPS Area web site).
            </cref></t>

            <t><cref>[TEMPLATE TODO] if you have any read-write and/or read-create objects, please
                describe their specific sensitivity or vulnerability. RFC 2669 has a very good example.
            </cref></t>


            <t>There are a number of management objects defined in this MIB module
                with a MAX-ACCESS clause of read-write and/or read-create. Such objects
                may be considered sensitive or vulnerable in some network environments.
                The support for SET operations in a non-secure environment without
                proper protection can have a negative effect on network operations.
                These are the tables and objects and their
                sensitivity/vulnerability:</t>

            <t><list style="symbols">
                <t></t>

                <!--
      <t><cref>[TEMPLATE TODO] writeable tables and managed objects that could be especially disruptive
      if abused and the associated security risks should be spelled out.</cref></t>
                -->
            </list></t>

            <t><cref>[TEMPLATE TODO] else if there are no read-write or read-create objects in your MIB module,
                use the following boilerplate paragraph.</cref></t>

            <t>There are no management objects defined in this MIB module that have
                a MAX-ACCESS clause of read-write and/or read-create. So, if this MIB
                module is implemented correctly, then there is no risk that an intruder
                can alter or create any management objects of this MIB module via direct
                SNMP SET operations.</t>

            <t><cref>For all MIB modules you must evaluate whether any readable objects
                are sensitive or vulnerable (for instance, if they might reveal customer
                information or violate personal privacy laws such as those of the
                European Union if exposed to unathorized parties).</cref></t>

            <t>Some of the readable objects in this MIB module (i.e., objects with a
                MAX-ACCESS other than not-accessible) may be considered sensitive or
                vulnerable in some network environments. It is thus important to control
                even GET and/or NOTIFY access to these objects and possibly to even
                encrypt the values of these objects when sending them over the network
                via SNMP. These are the tables and objects and their
                sensitivity/vulnerability: <list style="symbols">
                    <t></t>

                    <t><cref>[TEMPLATE TODO] you should explicitly list by name any readable objects that
                        are sensitive or vulnerable and the associated security risks should
                        be spelled out.</cref></t>

                </list></t>

            <t><cref>[TEMPLATE TODO] The following three boilerplate paragraphs
                should not be changed without very good reason. Changes will almost
                certainly require justification during IESG review.</cref></t>

            <t>SNMP versions prior to SNMPv3 did not include adequate security.
                Even if the network itself is secure (for example by using IPsec),
                there is no control as to who on the secure network is
                allowed to access and GET/SET (read/change/create/delete) the objects
                in this MIB module.</t>

            <t>   Implementations SHOULD provide the security features described by the
                SNMPv3 framework (see [RFC3410]), and implementations claiming compliance
                to the SNMPv3 standard MUST include full support for authentication and
                privacy via the User-based Security Model (USM) [RFC3414] with the AES
                cipher algorithm [RFC3826]. Implementations MAY also provide support for
                the Transport Security Model (TSM) [RFC5591] in combination with a secure
                transport such as SSH [RFC5592] or TLS/DTLS [RFC6353]. </t>

            <t>Further, deployment of SNMP versions prior to SNMPv3 is NOT
                RECOMMENDED. Instead, it is RECOMMENDED to deploy SNMPv3 and to enable
                cryptographic security. It is then a customer/operator responsibility to
                ensure that the SNMP entity giving access to an instance of this MIB
                module is properly configured to give access to the objects only to
                those principals (users) that have legitimate rights to indeed GET or
                SET (change/create/delete) them.</t>
        </section>

    </middle>

    <back>

        <!-- References Section -->

        <!-- Section 4.7f of [RFC2223bis] specifies the requirements for the
       references sections.  In particular, there MUST be separate lists of
       normative and informative references, each in a separate section.
       The style SHOULD follow that of recently published RFCs.

       The standard MIB boilerplate available at
      the OPS Area web site includes lists of
       normative and informative references that MUST appear in all IETF
       specifications that contain MIB modules.  If items from other MIB
       modules appear in an IMPORTS statement in the Definitions section,
       then the specifications containing those MIB modules MUST be included
       in the list of normative references.  When items are imported from an
       IANA-maintained MIB module the corresponding normative reference
       SHALL reference the on-line version of that MIB module.  It is the
       policy of the RFC Editor that all references must be cited in the
       text;  such citations MUST appear in the overview section where
       documents containing imported definitions (other than those already
       mentioned in the MIB boilerplate) are required to be mentioned (cf.
       Section 3.2).

    In general, each normative reference SHOULD reference the most recent
    version of the specification in question.
    -->

        <references title="Normative References">
            <!-- [TEMPLATE TODO] rfc2119, 2578, 2579, and 2580 are required to support MIB
          module boilerplate text. -->

            &rfc2119;

            &rfc2578;

            &rfc2579;

            &rfc2580;

        </references>

        <references title="Informative References">

            <!--  RFC3410 is required to support the boilerplate text.-->
            &rfc2223;
            &rfc3410;

            &rfc2629;

            &rfc4181;

        </references>

        <references title="URL References">
            <reference anchor="idguidelines">
                <front>
                    <title>http://www.ietf.org/ietf/1id-guidelines.txt</title>
                    <author>
                        <organization>IETF Internet Drafts editor</organization>
                    </author>
                    <date year=""></date>
                </front>
            </reference>
            <reference anchor="idnits">
                <front>
                    <title>http://www.ietf.org/ID-Checklist.html</title>
                    <author>
                        <organization>IETF Internet Drafts editor</organization>
                    </author>
                    <date year=""></date>
                </front>
            </reference>
            <reference anchor="xml2rfc">
                <front>
                    <title>http://xml.resource.org</title>
                    <author>
                        <organization>XML2RFC tools and documentation</organization>
                    </author>
                    <date year=""></date>
                </front>
            </reference>
            <reference anchor="ops">
                <front>
                    <title>http://www.ops.ietf.org</title>
                    <author>
                        <organization>the IETF OPS Area</organization>
                    </author>
                    <date year=""></date>
                </front>
            </reference>
            <reference anchor="ietf">
                <front>
                    <title>http://tools.ietf.org</title>
                    <author>
                        <organization>IETF Tools Team</organization>
                    </author>
                    <date year=""></date>
                </front>
            </reference>

        </references>
    </back>
</rfc>